

sonialahcene.com linkedin.com/sonialahcene contact@sonialahcene.com +44 (0) 7977 693 635

Passionate Global Digital Design Lead and Design Manager with years of experience in eCommerce, digital strategy and web design. Very organised and self-motivated, I love the challenge of developing best-in-class designs to create outstanding brand and customer experiences on all digital touchpoints.



## LONDON, UK

Interested in fully remote opportunities



#### **AREAS OF EXPERTISE**

eCommerce

**FMCG** 

Digital Brand Strategy

App & Web Design

Digital Innovation

Creative Direction

ediive Direction

Team Management



## **SKILLS & SOFTWARE**

Creative • Self-driven • Analytical • Fine eye for detail

UX • UI • Branding • CX •Illustration • Infographic• Image compositing

Adobe XD • Prototyping • User tests (UserTesting)

Photoshop • Illustrator • InDesign

HTML • CSS

AEM (Adobe Experience
Manager) • JIRA • Confluence
• Visual Studio Code

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **RECKITT, LONDON**

## Global Digital Design Lead, Nutrition (2021 - present)

Leading the global digital design strategy for Reckitt's Nutrition Business Unit (IFCN and VMS) to support digital transformation, drive conversion online, and improve the brand experience through digital innovations.

- Amazon A+ and B+ toolkit: leading the creation of an Amazon design toolkit for local markets to implement the new Enfamil brand purpose and VBL. Briefing design agencies to create B+ and A+ asset packs. Creating pixel-perfect prototypes for stakeholders. Writing user tests and producing analysis reports.
- Amazon design guidelines: creating global guidelines and a resource hub on SharePoint to help local eCommerce teams design best-in-class content for the digital shelf to increase CR and offer amazing CX. Collaborating with design and eCommerce agencies to identify main design drivers for conversion.
- Digital Design Consulting: supported the Nutrition R&D team with the Reckitt Nutrition Institute website redesign. Identified digital agency partners for the project, led product development strategy (mobile-first, user-centric and MVP approach for launch), and helped with website QA.
- Digital Innovations: introduced AI technology to our team and design projects (found the right partners in the US and produced initial briefs). Concept and design of a gamified digital loyalty card and D2C widget to better understand customers' needs, pain points and behaviours through data collection.
- Ways of Working: implementing new streamlined and more efficient ways of working within our team and with our digital agencies (digital-first approach, more agile project management, cloud technology for better collaboration...)

#### QVC UK, LONDON

In charge of the accurate and timely production of QVC's digital platforms, creating a seamless experience for millions of customers. From Digital Designer to Design Manager, my role at QVC has quickly evolved into a more strategic position with increased responsibilities.

#### Digital Design Manager (2018 - 2021)

- Leading the creative direction of digital content for the website, apps and marketing emails. Design review and sign-off of all digital assets.
- Managing and mentoring a team of Digital Designers and Web Publishers. Coordinating and prioritising work. Recruiting and training new team members.
- Overseeing platform upgrades and app releases, liaising with product owners and engineering teams, establishing roadmaps and defining best practices for content production.
- Implemented QVC new branding on digital platforms: created design guidelines and assets libraries, improving consistency and increasing productivity, while allowing flexibility and creativity for the designers.



# Global Digital Design Lead



### **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor in Visual Arts (2012)

University Panthéon Sorbonne Paris, France Visual Art, History of Art, Philosophy of Art

# Master in Management (2007-2011)

**EDHEC Business School** Lille, France Focus in Marketing and Communications



#### **LANGUAGES**

English

French

Spanish

• • 0 0



### **INTERESTS**

Baking baguettes

T-shirt design

Doodling

Doing backflips on trampolines

- Documenting processes and best practices in the team's wiki (CMS module guide, design workflows, onboarding guides, etc.).
- · Improving workflows and processes for the eCommerce and Design teams (JIRA training, improved briefs, best practices, etc.).
- Designing web pages and digital assets for campaigns and high-profile brands.

## Lead Digital Designer (2017 - 2018)

- Designed and built major cross-platform digital campaigns (Christmas, Black Friday, Holiday Shop, etc.).
- · Created UX documentation, photo briefs and assets used across all platforms and channels.
- Mentored other designers and led creative direction.
- Improved Design team's productivity by creating Photoshop templates.
- Streamlined work processes (new file naming convention, JIRA functionalities...)
- Helped recruit new Designers and Publishers. Trained new team members.
- Deputised for the Design Manager until being promoted Manager.

## Digital Designer (2017)

- Created high-quality assets for the Home, Garden and Electronics departments
- Designed, built and published web pages in AEM.
- Elaborated conceptual briefs for the in-house photo studio.

### SONIA L CREATION, LTD

## Freelance Graphic Designer (2015 - 2017)

Digital, graphic & design consulting services for renowned brands and design agencies.

- Key areas of expertise: digital & graphic design, illustration and design consulting.
- Brands and agencies: Timberland / GE / LinkedIn / Hootsuite / Brands2Life / The Story Lab / Mediablaze Group / Kaplan / Le Robert

#### LADBROKES, LONDON

## Web & Graphic Designer (2015 - 2016)

- · Designed and built two Google Sites for the Security & Compliance and Enterprise Architecture teams.
- Developed the branding and visual identity of both projects.
- Designed merchandising items and communication materials.

# ORANGE LABS UK, LONDON

## Communications Executive (2012 - 2014)

- Responsible for the internal and external communication strategy.
- Developed new branding: logos, visual assets, communication materials.
- Designed and built Orange Labs' website (EZ Publish CMS).
- Created and managed Orange Labs' intranet using Wordpress (HTML/CSS).
- Designed merchandising items for events.



## LOUIS VUITTON, PARIS

## Corporate Press Officer (2011)

- Organised a press trip for journalists from Korea, Hong Kong and Taiwan to visit Louis Vuitton's new luxury leather goods workshop in France.
- Supervised press kits production with in-house creatives and design agencies.
- Oversaw two press days and presented Louis Vuitton publications to journalists.
- · Edited press reviews, gathered and analysed media alerts.
- · Assisted PR officers on various projects and events.

## ALLIANCE FRANÇAISE, WASHINGTON DC

#### Communication Assistant & Event Coordinator (2009-2010)

- Coordinated more than a hundred cultural events (screenings, concerts, theatre plays, festivals, etc.).
- Led a cross-promotion collaboration with the Corcoran Gallery in Washington DC.
- Maintained the website and designed promotional materials for events.
- Helped produce events by suggesting artists and negotiating their fees.
- Negotiated low rates for technical equipment and lodging for groups of artists.
- Produced reports on the trends and evolution of the cultural department (attendance, visibility, accounting).

## **VISIT MY WEBSITE**

sonialahcene.com

